<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eike Rabetian</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eike Rabetian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description> I do mostly backend engineering. I love python and ZEN of Python. Django, FastApi, Java, Distributed systems, SQL/NoSQL, Docker, etc. Now Lead Backend Engineer @shipup I enjoy learning new things. The queue is at Go, Better System Design!, ML/AI on my list of learning new things. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>ichat - is an online support service for MTN-Irancell. shipup.net - is a company specialized in technology and shipping industry. Ahura - a God like Serializer for God like Developers. SAY - an employment related search engine for job listings with screening and other stuff. Auction Portal - a portal for ordering sim cards and business cards. Hi Estate - a real estate business via IT-based solutions. BackEnd Developer University - a backend developer learning path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker, Celery and Queues</title>
      <link>/blog/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/third/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of blogs on how to setup docker and celery for development, but none of them are really practical or like a real world example of development.
So I&amp;rsquo;m gonna show how I setup celery with docker while I have a few different celery queues for development.
Setup Celery and Docker when you only have one queue :
Dockerfile FROM python:3.8 ENV LANG=C.UTF-8 LC_ALL=C.UTF-8 PYTHONUNBUFFERED=1 WORKDIR / COPY requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Married To Any Tech Stack</title>
      <link>/blog/fourth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fourth/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done some observation. If you look at job postings in big companies, they always post their job positions with the title &amp;ldquo;Software engineer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Senior software engineer&amp;rdquo;. While if you look at other companies which are just startups or not that big or might not be very famous, they always post their job offers with the title &amp;ldquo;{Some_Language} developer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Senior {Some_Language} developer&amp;rdquo;.
Now what&amp;rsquo;s the difference here? A really good software engineer isn&amp;rsquo;t bound to any specific tool or technology!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Questions, Obvious Answers, Hidden Details</title>
      <link>/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>You want to know how good is someone at Python? You don&amp;rsquo;t need to ask strange obscure questions. Just ask for simple questions which has some hidden technology details behind it.
Like : how do you do a membership test in python?!
Now everyone knows how to do a membership test! You just check if a collection of items contain a specific item. Something like ;
if number in list_of_numbers: # Do something  But what not everybody knows is the time complexity of membership testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websites You Need To Bookmark As A Programmer</title>
      <link>/blog/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/second/</guid>
      <description>I was personally fascinated by the materials in these websites. Every time I look at the work has been done on these sites I get a small tangling feeling in my head. To be honest I&amp;rsquo;m blown away by some of em.
Learning to program isn&amp;rsquo;t just about learning the syntax or how to just combine things together. As Zi Chong Kao says : &amp;ldquo;Learning to program is learning a mental model&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>